All right, great.
حسناً، عظيم.
So that takes care of our first change.
سيهتم بالتغيير الأول.
So this is perfect timing.
لذلك فإنه التوقيت المثالي.
Because I have great news for you.
لأنيي لدي أخبار سارة لك.
Our designer has just finished the assets of our app, so
قد انتهى مصممنا من تصميم أصول تطبيقنا، لذلك
we can go ahead and add them to our project now.
يمكننا المتابعة وإضافتها إلى مشروعنا الآن.
And by the way I use the term asset to refer to the images the designer
وبالمناسبة استخدم أصول المصطلحات للإشارة إلى الصور التي
provided for us.
قدمها المصمم لنا.
An asset can refer to photos, logos, illustrations,
يمكن ان تشير كلمة أصول إلى صور، أو شعارات، أو رسوم توضيحية،
media files, or even text documents.
أو ملفات وسائط، أو مستندات نصية حتى.
But in this case, we're referring to the illustrations of Mewok app.
ولكن في هذه الحالة، سنشير إلى الرسوم التوضيحية للتطبيق ميوك.
Now you may hear the term asset drop,
ربما تسمع الآن مصطلح انسدال الأصول،
which means that the designer is handing over a group of assets to us.
الذي يعني أن المُصمم يوفر لنا مجموعة من الأصول.
Even if our designer hadn't given the illustrations to us,
حتى إذا لم يوفر لنا مُصممنا رسومًا توضيحية،
note that we wouldn't be completely blocked waiting for them.
نلاحظ أنه لم يتم حظرنا تماماً، سننتظرها.
We could still make progress on steps three and
ما زالنا نحرز تقدماً في الخطوات الثالثة
four by using placeholder data.
والرابعة باستخدام بيانات نائبة.
So it's important for us to get along as far as we can,
لذا من المهم لنا أن نتقدم إلى أقصى حد ممكن،
even if we don't have everything needed to finish the job.
حتى إذا لم يكن لدينا كل ما نحتاجه لإكمال المهمة.
All right, there are a lot of images in that asset drop.
حسناً، يوجد الكثير من الصور في القائمة المنسدلة الأصول.
So let's take a look at the files that were received.
دعنا نلقي نظرة على الملفات التي استلمناها.
I'd like you to follow along.
أريدك أن تتابع ذلك.
Go ahead and pause the video and click on this Downloads It button.
تابع ذلك وأوقف تشغيل الفيديو مؤقتًا وانقر فوق زر التنزيلات.
So once that whole ZIP file has downloaded onto your computer,
بمجرد تنزيل ملفZIP بالكامل على جهاز الكمبيوتر،
I'd like you to go ahead and click open the Assets folder.
أريدك أن تتابع ذلك وتنقر لفتح في مجلد الأصول.
So, inside we see five different folders.
نرى في الداخل خمسة مجلدات مختلفة.
So drawable HDPI, MDPI,
مجلد HDPI، وMDPI،
XHDPI, XXHDPI and XXXHDPI.
وHDPI، وXXHDPI، وXXXHDPI القابل للرسم.
So let's click open each one and explore around.
دعنا ننقر لفتح كل مجلد منها واستكشاف ما به.
So clicking open this HDPI one, whoa!
ننقر لفتح HDPI هذا، توقف!
We see there's a bunch of images here.
نرى هنا مجموعة من الصور.
So, how about I click open the family daughter image.
ماذا عن النقر لفتح صورة الابنة في العائلة.
So, clicking it open shows a preview of it.
إن النقر فوقها يعرض معاينة لها.
So, that brings up the question: what are all these other folders for?
يطرح ذلك سؤالاً: ما الذي تخصه جميع هذه المجلدات الأخرى؟
How about I click open this triple x one.
ماذا عن النقر فوق لفتح الملف الذي يحتوي على ثلاثة أحرف "X".
So, clicking the family daughter image underneath the XXXHDPI folder
النقر فوق صورة الابنة في العائلة أسفل المجلد XXXHDPI
shows the same family daughter image, but it's much larger this time.
يوضح صورة ابنة العائلة نفسها ولكنها بحجم أكبر بكثير هذه المرة.
So why do you think our designer gave us multiple versions of the same icon, but
لماذا تعتقد أن مُصممنا قدم لنا إصدارات متعددة من الرمز نفسه، لكن
at different sizes?
بأحجام مختلفة؟
So for this next exercise, I'd like it you to browse through the files and
في هذا التمرين التالي، أريدك أن تتصفح الملفات
folders from our designer.
والمجلدات الواردة من مُصممنا.
The link to the assets is in the notes below.
رابط الانتقال إلى الأصول موجود في الملاحظات أدناه.
And then I'd like you to try to answer these questions.
وأريدك أن تحاول الإجابة عن هذه الأسئلة.
Why are there different draw-able folders?
لماذا توجد مجلدات مختلفة قابلة للرسم؟
And, why are there multiple versions versions of the same image.
ولماذا توجد إصدارات متعددة من الصورة نفسها.
So make some observations and guesses about what is happening.
قم بإجراء بعض الملاحظات والتخمينات حول ما يحدث.
I know we haven't covered these topics yet, so
أعرف أننا لم نتطرق إلى هذه الموضوعات حتى الآن
try to answer these questions as best as you can.
لذا حاول أن تجيب عن هذه الأسئلة بأفضل إجابة ممكنة.